<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: youtube | meh...]]></title>
  <link href="http://sch1zo.github.com/blog/categories/youtube/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://sch1zo.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-01-30T23:05:20+01:00</updated>
  <id>http://sch1zo.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Andreas Eger]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[using my ec2 instance to get a US IP]]></title>
    <link href="http://sch1zo.github.com/blog/2011/08/12/using-my-ec2-instance-to-get-a-us-ip/"/>
    <updated>2011-08-12T00:00:00+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://sch1zo.github.com/blog/2011/08/12/using-my-ec2-instance-to-get-a-us-ip</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Today I was surfing around and once again I got that ugly GEMA message on a
youtube music video which prevented me from watching it. In the last months
more and more videos got blocked this way and makes having a german IP a pain.</p>

<p>But than I remembered that I can set up a Micro Instance in one of the US
datacentrers and route my web traffic through it.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>So what are my options to do this?</p>

<ul>
<li>setting up a proxy server on that instance</li>
<li>establish a ssh tunnnel and use that as local proxy</li>
<li>set up a VPN server on the instance and use that to reroute my traffic</li>
</ul>


<p>Because I don't like having to set a proxy in each and every browser and app I
have and than always having to keep my tunnel open I decided to look into the
VPN solution. After all I can fall back to the tunnel at any time - for
example if I need to connect to another VPN and still want to use a US IP or
if I want to be connected to one of my other servers without having the signal
bounce to the US and back.</p>

<p>After deleting my existing instance(which was at the european data center) I
looked at the available Community AMIs. One of them was called <strong>OpenVPN
Access Server</strong> and after looking at the related site I thought this is
exactly what I wanted and is free for 2 concurrent users. Theres also a
<a href="http://openvpn.net/index.php/access-server/docs/admin-guides/499%0A-openvpn-access-server-ami.html">guide</a> on their site which describes how to make the
initial setup. And even better it perfectly fits in the Free Tier Plan.</p>

<p>Unfortunately I could nowhere find what the user is with which I can connect
via ssh to the instance. After some more searching and trying I figured its
the user <strong>ubuntu</strong> - nice of them to mention that nowhere in the guide.</p>

<p>But even without even having to connect a single time via SSH to the instance
it had started a nice webUI with full Admin interface and everything you need
to connect to the VPN. It even offers pre-configured OpenVPN Clients for
Windows and Mac and a guide for Unix.</p>

<p>So now all I have to do is tell the OpenVPN Client to connect to my instance
and I'm good to go. Now I just have to keep a look at my monthly traffic -
there are <em>only</em> 15GB in and 15GB out in the Free Tier Plan. Could become a
problem considering the fact I now have access to hulu/pandora and others.</p>

<p>This usage doesn't has anything to do with my initial plan to explore the
cloud but an EC2 instance is basically just a virtual server with some
additional services strapped on. Still I will look into the other services of
the Free Tier Plan. I'm especially interested in the SimpleDB service,
unfortunately only 25 <em>machine hours</em> are free per month - whatever they mean
with machine hour. There are more <em>more cloudy</em> things I have in mind and will
test at some point.</p>

<p>PS: I also found a really nice monthly activities page for your account, shows
exactly what and how much of it you used and how much it costs.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
