<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: amazon | meh...]]></title>
  <link href="http://sch1zo.github.com/blog/categories/amazon/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://sch1zo.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-01-19T19:01:50+01:00</updated>
  <id>http://sch1zo.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Andreas Eger]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Messing around with the Amazon Cloud Part 1]]></title>
    <link href="http://sch1zo.github.com/blog/2011/07/15/messing-around-with-the-amazon-cloud-part-1/"/>
    <updated>2011-07-15T00:00:00+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://sch1zo.github.com/blog/2011/07/15/messing-around-with-the-amazon-cloud-part-1</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>after getting the EC2 Instance up and running its time to install a basic
development environment.</p>

<ul>
<li>zsh and screen makes as expected no problems.</li>
<li>vim is unfortunately not compiled with ruby and I couldn't find another one in the repository so it has to work without it</li>
<li>rvm again no problem. As I'm writing this post ruby 1.9.2 is compiling, which given the power of a micro instance is slow perhaps to slow to do anything with it, but time will see.</li>
</ul>


<!-- more -->


<p>Next time setting up such a machine it may be no bad idea to get a bigger
instance for a few hours, just to make the compiling faster.</p>

<p>What surprised me was how minimal the installed linux were, no unnecessary
packages just the stuff I want.</p>

<p>Next steps:</p>

<ul>
<li>compiling nginx (with passenger) - this could take a while given the speed of the instance</li>
<li>running a few of my small sinatra and rails apps</li>
<li>will this instance be fast enough to do development?</li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Messing around with the Amazon Cloud Part 0]]></title>
    <link href="http://sch1zo.github.com/blog/2011/07/15/messing-around-with-the-amazon-cloud-part-0/"/>
    <updated>2011-07-15T00:00:00+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://sch1zo.github.com/blog/2011/07/15/messing-around-with-the-amazon-cloud-part-0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>so out of curiosity I just registered for <a href="http://aws.amazon.com/">Amazon Web
Services</a> and my plan is to just use the free tier
Amazon provides <a href="http://aws.amazon.com/free">link</a>.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>Right now after about half an hour I have my first micro instance up and it
runs <a href="http://aws.amazon.com/amazon-linux-ami/">Amazon Linux (Beta)</a>. Thats a
maintained and supported Linux image which just fits in the free tier plan. As
far as I can tell it has its background in the Red Hat camp and uses yum as
package manager.</p>

<p>The Management Console is at first glance is nice but you definitely have to
get the hang of it. There's many stuff to configure and setup, but more on
that later.</p>

<p>First downer: I couldn't get the Archlinux images running, will have to look
into that at some point.</p>

<p>Another weird thing is that once you are in the management console your not
really have control over your costs, but at least when you create a new
instance it will show you if it will fit in the free plan.</p>

<p>Next Steps are</p>

<ul>
<li>install zsh, vim, screen, ruby - rvm</li>
<li>make the necessary setup for the above (basically import my rc files)</li>
<li>watch how the micro instance performs</li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
